A Guide to the Fran Poston Photograph Collection, 2003
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Fran Poston Photograph Collection 2003
Thomas Balch Library
VC 0007
35 items
35 photographs of historic downtown Leesburg, Virginia.
Fran Poston
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research
Acquisition Information
Mary Fishback, Leesburg, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2006.0165
Historical Information
In the 1750's Leesburg emerged as a small settlement at the crossroads of the Carolina and Alexandria Roads, two major trading routes. It was recognized as the county seat for Loudoun in 1758 by the Virginia General Assembly. When the British marched on Washington, D.C. in 1812, the town served as a temporary capital. During that time, many important archives were brought to Leesburg for safekeeping including the Articles of Confederation, the U.S. Constitution and the Declaration of Independence. During the Civil War, the town was recognized by both the Union and the Confederacy for its strategic position. Throughout the Civil War, both Union and Confederate troops marched through the area and the town changed hands over 100 times. Leesburg was also the site of the Battle of Balls Bluff in 1861. Throughout the years, Leesburg has been visited by a number of prominent figures including George Washington, the Marquis de Lafayette, Herbert Hoover, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Harry Byrd. Additionally, both Westmoreland Davis and George C. Marshall lived in the area. Leesburg's picturesque and well-preserved Historic District was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1970. The town continues to serves as the seat of government for one of the nation's fastest growing counties in the nation.
Scope and Content
Fran Poston was born in Leesburg and raised in Loudoun County. Her family has a long history here having been in the area for over 200 years. Poston has had an interest in photography throughout her life and is a part-time professional photographer. The photographs in this collection were taken as a collaborative effort with Mary Fishback, who used a number of images in her book, Images of America: Leesburg. Poston also took photographs that Fishback used in Loudoun County People and Places. The photographs in this collection were taken in 2003 to document Leesburg in that year. Some of those photographs were reproduced in Mary Fishback's Images of America: Leesburg, which provides a brief summary of notable people and events in the history of the town.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Fishback, Mary. Leesburg. Images of America. Charleston, SC: Arcadia, 2003. 975.528 FIS
Poston, Fran, interview with Lisa Dezarn, April 2008.
Smith, Kathryn Gettings, Evelyn D. Causey, and Edna Johnston. Exploring Leesburg: Guide to History and Architecture. Leesburg, Va: Town of Leesburg, 2003. 975.528 SMI
Town of Leesburg. "History." http://www.leesburgva.gov/about/History/ (accessed 26 April 2008).
Other Finding Aid
Past Perfect Catalog records
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
Fishback, Mary. Leesburg. Images of America. Charleston, SC: Arcadia, 2003. 975.528 FIS
Contents List
  - Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Market Street looking east from the road in front of the Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Town of Leesburg Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Town of Leesburg Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Town of Leesburg Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Laurel Brigade Inn, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Intersection of Edwards Ferry Road and East Market Street, facing Barrister Building, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Intersection of Edwards Ferry Road and East Market Street, facing Barrister Building, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Intersection of Edwards Ferry Road and East Market Street, facing Barrister Building, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Intersection of Edwards Ferry Road and East Market Street, facing Barrister Building, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Intersection of Edwards Ferry Road and East Market Street, facing Barrister Building, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Parking Garage for Loudoun County Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Parking Garage for Loudoun County Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Parking Garage for Loudoun County Government Center, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Harrison Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Harrison Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Harrison Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Overview Shot of Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Harrison Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center & Parking Garage, Loudoun Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Loudoun Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Government Center, Loudoun Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse and Courthouse Lawn, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Confederate Monument in front of Loudoun County Courthouse, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Confederate Monument in front of Loudoun County Courthouse, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse, N. King Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse, N. King Street view, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Old Leesburg Baptist Church, 7 Wirt Street, SW Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Russell Baker House, West Market Street, Leesburg, VA, 2003
  - Loudoun County Courthouse, Leesburg, VA, 2003